paclii.org 2006-12-10

# PacLII - About PacLII: Privacy Policy

PacLII's privacy policies are based on respect for international standards of information privacy protection. 

## A. Information concerning usage of PacLII

**A1.** PacLII collects information which identifies, for each page accessed on PacLII, the network identity of the machine which has accessed it. PacLII retains this usage information for purposes of network analysis, usage analysis, and research into usage patterns for the purpose of improving PacLII services. Access to and use of this information is restricted to PacLII management and staff, and to researchers working on PacLII projects and subject to an agreement to adhere to this Privacy Policy.

**A2.** PacLII does not disclose or publish information which identifies individual machines, or potentially identifying sub-groupings of addresses, without consent. PacLII does publish aggregated information about usage patterns.

**A3.** PacLII reserves the right to gather more extensive information that stated above (i) about any attempted access to PacLII which raise security issues (and, where necessary, to make disclosures to relevant authorities); and (ii) for network analyses on an occasional basis.

## B. Personal information contained in PacLII databases

**B1.** Some PacLII databases contain personal information, including the decisions of Courts and Tribunals, and the reports of Royal Commissions. PacLII publishes these databases with the consent of the public bodies concerned. It is the responsibility of the public bodies which provide these databases to PacLII to determine, subject to the requirements of the laws under which they operate, the appropriate balance between the privacy interests of individuals and the public interests in dissemination of the information. In particular, if personal data is to be anonymised before publication, this is done by the public body concerned. PacLII does not and can not censor part or all of the information provided by these public bodies for publication.

**B2.** PacLII does not consent to the contents of these databases being indexed by other web sites. PacLII attempts to prevent such indexing occurring by placing these database outside the permitted scope of web 'crawlers', 'robots' or 'spiders' that adhere to the voluntary Robot Exclusion Standard

PacLII also monitors whether any robots attempt to index these databases in disregard of this Standard, and takes steps to exclude any that do so from any access to PacLII.

**B3.** PacLII users should note that there are legal limitations on the use, publication and dissemination of some personal information contained in PacLII databases. 

**B4.** If any person considers that any case in a PacLII database may contain information which it should not include, PacLII suggests that they should contact the Registrar of the Court or Tribunal concerned, setting out the reasons why there is information in a case which should not be published. The Court or Tribunal is then in a position to inform all previous recipients of the case of any matters that need to be changed. 

**PacLII reserves the right to exclude access to its databases by users or sites that are in apparent breach of any such legal requirements.**

If you have any comments or suggestions in relation to this policy, please **send us some mail**.

* * *

**PacLII:** Copyright Policy **|** Disclaimers **|** Privacy Policy **|** Feedback   
URL: _http://www.paclii.org/paclii/privacy.html_
